hello everybody and welcome to
section 8.6 of the textbook in
content video form comparison
operators for strings so what
this section talks about is kind
of what we've been mentioning
this whole time is that python
is case sensitive and here's why
right so the character capital
a has a ordinal value of 65.
Similarly, the lowercase a
has an ordinal value of 97.
And when we're doing comparisons, like if
we were to jump over into our code space,
and
if we were to do some kind of a
comparison, like we could say, if a
equals a, or maybe we could even
just say print a equals a and we
would expect to see that this would
tell us false right because the
ordinal value of a is 65 and the
ordinal value of lowercase a is 97 and
so when we compare these two they
are not actually equal to each
other because they've got that case
sensitivity in there. Same thing
would happen if we said like Chelsea
Harding versus lowercase Chelsea
Harding. These should not equal
true either, so two falses. Alright,
you can always check a string's
ordinal value by using the built-in
function ord. So if we were to
print ord for the character a and
then do the same thing. We could
see the ordinal value for little a.
Oh my goodness. We could also
do it for any other character.
So I don't know. I'm curious about
the ordinal value for the letter R.
And we could see what those give us.
65,
79, and 114.
So one more thing just to show you.
does 65 equal
big A?
And hopefully the answer is
true. It's actually false. So,
oh sorry, that's because that's a string.
Ford A. I was like, that
was supposed to be true.
Now it should be true.
Because the ordinal value for A is 65.
So that's about everything for this
content video. Thank you for watching.
Thank you.